<tutorial>
  <name>Setting up a MySQL database</name>
  <description>Setting up a MySQL database is typically the first step for a new
    user of BinNavi. This database is used to store the data of disassembled
    files as well as all the changes and annotations the user makes while
    working.&lt;br/&gt; &lt;br/&gt;
In this tutorial the user learns about the following concepts:&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Configuring a connection to a database server&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Creating a new database&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Connecting to the new database&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
  <steps>
    <step>
      <action>0</action>
      <description>This tutorial shows you how to set up a MySQL database for
        use with BinNavi. This database is used to store disassembled data and
        all the additional information (like comments or tags) you add during
        your work.&lt;br/&gt; &lt;br/&gt;
There are no prior requirements necessary for working through this tutorial. You
can start with this tutorial right now.&lt;br/&gt; &lt;br/&gt;
Please click on the Next button to continue.
</description>
    </step>
    <step>
      <action>-7789885643476931774</action>
      <description>On the left-hand side of the BinNavi main window you can see
        the so called Project Tree. This Project Tree is the starting point of
        any work with BinNavi. It shows the configured databases and - once a
        connection to a database was established - all the necessary information
        from the database that is important for your work. The Project Tree can
        be used to configure MySQL databases for BinNavi too.&lt;br/&gt;
        &lt;br/&gt;
There are two different ways to create a new database configuration.&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Click the BinNavi/Add Database menu&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Right-click the Project Tree and click Add Database&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
Please note that the MySQL database you want to configure does not need to
exist. You can just go ahead and create a new database configuration now using
either of the two methods from above.  </description>
    </step>
    <step>
      <action>0</action>
      <description>You have successfully created a new BinNavi database
        configuration. The configuration options for this configuration should
        now be visible on the right side of the main window. If the
        configuration options are not visible, please click on the new database
        configuration in the Project Tree.&lt;br/&gt; &lt;br/&gt;
In the configuration settings you can specify the location of the MySQL database
you would like to use and the user data necessary to connect to the database.
Please enter your personal connection data into the text fields and press the
Next button to continue with this tutorial.  </description>
    </step>
    <step>
      <action>8784926684855833953</action>
      <description>Once you have entered the connection data to your database
        you can test whether BinNavi can establish a connection to that database
        using the Test Connection button.&lt;br/&gt; &lt;br/&gt;
Please note that the database you have configured does not have to exist yet. If
the database does not exist yet, BinNavi asks you if it should create the
database for you. This makes it easier for you to get started with new databases
because you do not have to create new databases manually on your database
server.&lt;br/&gt; &lt;br/&gt;
Please click on the Test Connection button now to complete this step of the
tutorial.  </description>
    </step>
    <step>
      <action>-9044865055464757942</action>
      <allowed>8784926684855833953</allowed>
      <description>If the connection to the database could be established you
        can now save your connection data using the Save button. When opening a
        database, only connection information that was saved is used. This makes
        it very important that you always click the Save button after changing
        database connection information.&lt;br/&gt; &lt;br/&gt;
If BinNavi could not establish the connection to the database, please check your
database connection settings and whether the MySQL database server you want to
connect to is running and accessible from your computer.&lt;br/&gt; &lt;br/&gt;
If BinNavi could establish the connection to the database please click the Save
button now.  </description>
    </step>
    <step>
      <action>-2369159756337681560</action>
      <allowed>-9044865055464757942</allowed>
      <allowed>8784926684855833953</allowed>
      <description>Congratulations. You have created your first database
        configuration. In the final step of this tutorial you will now load the
        content of the configured database. You can load a database doing any of
        &lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Double-click on the database in the Project Tree&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Select the database in the Project Tree and click the menu Database /
Connect to Database &lt;/li&gt; &lt;/ul&gt;
Please go ahead and connect to the new database now.
</description>
    </step>
    <step>
      <action>0</action>
      <description>If the connection to the database could be established you
        should now see additional entries in the Project Tree. These new entries
        represent various aspects of useful BinNavi data you can use during your
        work. Since the database you are working with was just created it is
        still completely empty. The next step would be to add useful disassembly
        data to the database. This is covered in the tutorial named Importing
        data from IDA Pro which you can work through next if you want
        to.&lt;br/&gt; &lt;br/&gt;
For now please click on the Next button to move on to the end of the tutorial.
</description>
    </step>
    <step>
      <action>0</action>
      <description>Congratulations. You have reached the end of this tutorial.
        You should now know how to set up a MySQL database for use with BinNavi.
        If you are having any problems with this tutorial or if you want to have
        more in-depth explanations of the configuration options we did not talk
        about in this tutorial, please take a look at the BinNavi
        manual.&lt;br/&gt; &lt;br/&gt;This tutorial ends when you click the Next
        button.
</description>
    </step>
  </steps>
</tutorial>
