<tutorial>
  <name>Importing data from IDA Pro</name>
  <description>One of the first aspects of working with disassembled data is to
    get the disassembled data from IDA Pro into the BinNavi database.&lt;br/&gt;
    &lt;br/&gt;
In this tutorial you will learn&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;how to use IDA Pro as a data source for BinNavi&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
  <steps>
    <step>
      <action>0</action>
      <description>This tutorial shows you how to use IDA Pro as a data source
        to get data into an existing MySQL database. To do this you will
        disassemble a test file in IDA Pro and tell BinNavi to convert the data
        from the created IDB file to the MySQL database. By the end of the
        tutorial, all disassembled data from the IDB file will be stored in the
        MySQL database and you can start working with the disassembled
        data.&lt;br/&gt; &lt;br/&gt;
Please click on the Next button to continue.
</description>
    </step>
    <step>
      <action>0</action>
      <description>Even though you can use any IDB file in this tutorial it is
        recommended that you disassemble the file primes.exe which you can find
        in the tutorials subdirectory of your BinNavi installation.&lt;br/&gt;
        &lt;br/&gt;      
Please disassemble this file now and save the disassembled data to an IDB file.
When you are done close IDA Pro. This last step is very important because IDA
Pro locks the IDB file as long as it is running and BinNavi can not import the
data from the IDB file while the IDB file is locked.&lt;br/&gt; &lt;br/&gt;
Please click on the Next button to continue.
</description>
    </step>
    <step>
      <action>0</action>
      <allowed>-2369159756337681560</allowed>
      <allowed>-9044865055464757942</allowed>
      <allowed>8784926684855833953</allowed>
      <allowed>-7789885643476931774</allowed>
      <description>This tutorial requires an existing MySQL database
        configuration. If you do not yet have a database configured please
        create the database configuration now.&lt;br/&gt; &lt;br/&gt;
Once you have created the database, please click on the Next button to continue.
</description>
    </step>
    <step>
      <action>-8750454886776173497</action>
      <allowed>-2369159756337681560</allowed>
      <allowed>-9044865055464757942</allowed>
      <allowed>8784926684855833953</allowed>
      <allowed>-7789885643476931774</allowed>
      <description>Now that the IDB file exists you can tell BinNavi to import
        the data from the IDB file into a database. You can use the following
        ways to start the import process: &lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Right-click the database in the Project Tree and click Import IDB
File&lt;/li&gt; &lt;li&gt;Right-click the Modules node of a database in the
Project Tree and click Import IDB File&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Select the database in the Project Tree and click the Database /
Import IDB File menu&lt;/li&gt; &lt;li&gt;Select the Modules folder in the
Project Tree and click the Module / Import IDB File menu&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
Whichever way you choose, you will be asked for the location of your IDA Pro
executable file (if you did configure that location previously) and the IDB file
you want to import. The rest of the import process is handled automatically by
BinNavi. If nothing goes wrong, you can find a new entry in the Modules node of
the Project Tree. This new entry primes.exe contains all the disassembled data
that was imported from the IDB file.&lt;br/&gt; &lt;br/&gt;
If you have not done so yet, you will also be asked to configure the location of
your IDA Pro executable. In the same dialog you can install the exporters you
want to use to get data from IDA Pro into BinNavi.  </description>
    </step>
    <step>
      <action>0</action>
      <allowed>-2369159756337681560</allowed>
      <allowed>-8750454886776173497</allowed>
      <description>If the import process of the IDB file was successful you can
        click the Next button to continue. If something went wrong you can now
        try to import the IDB file again.</description> </step>
    <step>
      <action>-5178343179269965998</action>
      <allowed>2804136480786366059</allowed>
      <description>If the module import was successful a new node that
        represents the BinNavi module of the IDB file should have appeared in
        the Project Tree. If the import was not successful please try to find
        out what went wrong and try import the IDB file again.&lt;br/&gt;
        &lt;br/&gt;      
In the final step of this tutorial we will load the BinNavi module so that you
can see the data of the module. You can load a module using any of the following
ways &lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Double-click on the primes.exe module node in the Project
Tree&lt;/li&gt; &lt;li&gt;Right-click the primes.exe module node and click the
Load Module menu&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Select the primes.exe module node and click the Module / Load Module
menu&lt;/li&gt; &lt;/ul&gt;
Please open the module now to continue.
</description>
    </step>
    <step>
      <action>0</action>
      <allowed>-5178343179269965998</allowed>
      <description>Now that the module is loaded you can see the functions of
        the module or other data of the module on the right-hand side of the
        main window when you select the module node or one of its children in
        the Project Tree.&lt;br/&gt;      &lt;br/&gt;
You have reached the end of this tutorial. You are now familiar with the concept
of modules and how to get data from IDA Pro into the database.&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
Please click on the Next button to finish this tutorial.
</description>
    </step>
  </steps>
</tutorial>
