<tutorial>
  <name>Using REIL</name>
  <description>One of the most important features for writing analysis scripts
    and plugins is REIL. REIL is a platform-independent Reverse Engineering
    Intermediate Language which you can use to write platform-independent
    analysis algorithms. This tutorial shows you how to use REIL.
  </description>
  <steps>
    <step>
      <action>-7167187997929184030</action>
      <action>-5295816457628962096</action>
      <allowed>-2369159756337681560</allowed>
      <allowed>-9044865055464757942</allowed>
      <allowed>8784926684855833953</allowed>
      <allowed>-7789885643476931774</allowed>
      <allowed>-8750454886776173497</allowed>
      <allowed>-5178343179269965998</allowed>
      <allowed>2804136480786366059</allowed>
      <description>Since REIL is primarily used from plugins and scripts, there
        are only two ways to access REIL from the GUI. Both of these options
        require an open flowgraph. Please open an arbitrary function now.
      </description>
    </step>
    <step>
      <action>3403011209340957215</action>
      <description>One way to access REIL is from the scripting dialog. Please
        open the scripting dialog of your flowgraph.  </description>
    </step>
    <step>
      <action>0</action>
      <description>In console mode you can simply enter commands like&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
print cg.view.reilCode&lt;br/&gt;
print cg.view.reilCode.graph&lt;br/&gt;
print cg.view.reilCode.graph.nodes&lt;br/&gt;
print cg.view.reilCode.graph.nodes[0]&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
to access the REIL code of your flowgraph.&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
When you are done playing around with REIL scripting please close the scripting
dialog again and click the Next button to continue.</description> </step>
    <step>
      <action>2478803857892102988</action>
      <description>Just using the scripting dialog to access REIL code is a bit
        unwieldly. BinNavi is a graph visualization tool after all, so it should
        be possible to show the generated REIL code of a view as a graph. This
        is indeed possible through the Graph / Transform / Show REIL Code menu
        of the graph window.&lt;br/&gt; &lt;br/&gt;
Please use this menu now to show the REIL code of your flowgraph.</description>
    </step>
    <step>
      <action>0</action>
      <description>This is the end of this tutorial already. You are now aware
        of all the ways to access REIL from the GUI. If you want to use REIL to
        write your own static analysis algorithms please see the BinNavi manual
        for detailed information and example algorithms.&lt;br/&gt; &lt;br/&gt;
Please click the Next button to finish this tutorial. Afterwards you can play
around with the REIL graph.</description> </step>
  </steps>
</tutorial>
